Guide to the Romanov Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6. "Tea at the farm" (at Oreander)
p. 4 1. "Her Majesty and I" (Anna)
2. The Grand Duchesses and tennis partners
3. On the tennis court: Rodionov, Tatiana, Anastasia, Nicholas, and Olga
4. Nicholas, Tatiana, Rodionov, and Marie
5. Tennis group: Nicholas with his three eldest daughters and partners
6. Nicholas
7. Nicholas and Alexandra with Marie, walking up the path to the tennis house for tea - at Livadia
8. Tea at the tennis house, Anna in the center
9. Nicholas and Rodionov at tennis
p. 5 1. The little house for tea after tennis
2. The Grand Duchesses on the tennis court
3. Nicholas
4. "
5. The Empress and Sablin
6. The Emperor, Tatiana, Rodionov, and Marie
7. The Empress
p. 6: Bazaar at Yalta 1. The Empress's table, with officers and the Grand Duchesses
2. The Empress selling goods made by her at her table
3. Alexandra at Oreander
4. Nicholas at tennis
5. Alexandra and her daughters
6. Nicholas playing tennis with Marie and Tatiana
7. The Emperor with General Voeikov, Livadia Palace
p. 7 1. The Empress with officers of the Black Sea Fleet
2. The Emperor and his children with Cossack officers of the Konvoy (Grabbe, their commandant is seen between Anastasia and Olga) at GHQ Moginav
3. The Imperial family in front of the barracks
4. The Empress in her carriage before the review
p. 8 1. The Empress and her daughters in a carriage for the review, Alexis and Nagorny (his sailor guard) in the foreground
2. The panoramic view from Livadia
3. The panorama from the park of Livadia Palace
p. 9 1. The magnificent view of sky, sea and mountains from Livadia
2. Tea at the farm
3. Tatiana
4. Butakov and the Emperor
5. "View from the balcony of the Tsar's study"
p. 10: "A visit to the dacha of Countess N" 1. "Alya [sister of Anna V. (Alexandra)] and I" (Anna)
2. "Ira and I" (Anna)
3. "The dacha of Countess N"
4. View from the balcony
5. "Countess N"
6. "Mama [Nadezda Rhiaronovna Taneeva] and Alya"
7. "Countess N"
p. 11: Livadia Park 1. View of the park surrounding the palace
2. "
3. View of the palace
p. 12: "A trip to Kazmandemiansk" 1. En route
2. "
3. The Emperor's little hunting cabin
4. The Emperor's suite: Count Grabbe, Nicholas, Prince Orloff, Voiekov, and Katkov
5. Nicholas at the head of a hiking party
6. At the little hunting lodge
7. View from the lodge
8. Nicholas and his hiking party
p. 13: "The walk to Kazmandemiansk" 1. Nicholas on the balcony of his hunting cabin
2. The Imperial family and suite on the hike
3. Nicholas on the balcony of his hunting cabin
4. The family and suite on the hike
5. View from the Tsar's hunting lodge
6. Anastasia and General Voiekov
7. Marie in the park at Livadia
p. 14 1. Nicholas with his daughters, Olga, Anastasia, and Tatiana
2. Nicholas with an officer on the walk to Kazmandemiansk
3. "Wild goats on the way"
4. The Imperial family en route
5. Alexandra in her pony chaise, the girls walking beside her
6. Nicholas en route
7. Nicholas with two officers of his suite en route
8. Alexandra in her pony chaise, Nicholas and the girls walking
p. 15: "Alupka" (Palace) 1. Autographed luncheon menu
2. Scenes of Alupka
3. Park of Alupka
4. "Sashka Vorontsov"
5. The park at Alupka
6. Panoramic view over the Black Sea; Livadia can be seen on the lower right
7. "Countess Vorontsova"
p. 16 1. "His Majesty at Oreander"
2. View from the farm over Livadia
3. Alexis riding with Derevanko
4. Nicholas in the arbor at Oreander
p. 17: Livadia 1. View of the palace from the driveway
2. Nicholas on the tennis court
3. The park of Livadia
4. View over the Black Sea
p. 18: Livadia 1. The old, small palace (where A. III died), postcard. There was also the old, large palace used before new palace was built in 1911 on top of it.
2. Nicholas
3. On the portico of the new palace - the Grand Duchesses with officers of the suite
4. Entry to Livadia park, postcard
5. Visiting a Jewish synagogue at Euptoria - Nicholas and Alexis
6. Nicholas and Alexis
p. 19: Livadia, postcards 1. Turkish gazebo
2. The palace
3. Livadia park
4. The palace
5. View from Livadia over the Black Sea
p. 20: Livadia 1. "The Imperial palace", postcard
2. "Livadia park", postcard
3. "The Imperial palace", postcard
4. "Livadia park", postcard
5. Visit of the Imperial family to the Jewish Synagogue at Eupatoria
6. Pierre Gilliard (French tutor) and his pupils Olga and Tatiana
p. 21: Livadia 1. The palace, postcard
2. The four Grand Duchesses on the balcony of the Tsar's hunting lodge
3. Livadia park, postcard
4. "Grand Duchess Olga and I (Anna) and the Dr. of the Sanatarium of the Red Cross" (the sanatarium in the Crimea funded by the Emperor and Empress)
5. Anna at Livadia
p. 22: "Chernovitsa" 1. The cathedral at Chernovitsa
2. View of the monastery
3. Park surrounding the monastery
4. On the porch of a monastery building
5. "Father Makary"
6. "At the house of Father Makary
7. A service at the monastery
p. 23 1. "Father Makary"
2. The village, near Chernovitsa
3. "On the river Tura"
4. Priests and villagers
5. On the river Tura
6. Father Makary
7. The woods
8. The river Tura
p. 24 1. Peasants of the village
2. Flood waters
3. "Tanichka" (Anna's niece)
4. Flood waters
5. Villagers attending to the flood
6. "Serezha" (Anna's brother)
p. 25: "Peterhof - fall 1914" 1. The Empress in her boudoir, lower Dacha-Aleksandria-Peterhof
2. "Serezha, Mama, Papa and Roy" (dog)
3. "Mother" (of Anna)
4. "Serezha" (Anna's brother)
5. Unidentified relative
6. A bridge at Peterhof
7. Serezha and unidentified relative
p. 26 1. Alexandra on the balcony of lower Dacha-Aleksandria-Peterhof
2. "
3. "
4. Olga and a small friend
5. Unidentified relative of Anna
6. The Empress
7. Serezha (Anna's brother) and unidentified woman
p. 27: "On the Standart" 1. Nicholas
2. Alexandra with Tatiana, Olga and Marie
3. Alexis
4. Alexandra
5. Nicholas and Alexandra on deck
6. Alexandra and her daughters
p. 28 1. A canal lock, Kronstadt
2. Nicholas and Alexandra on deck
3. Nicholas and Alexis
4. Marie and Olga
5. Pierre Gilliard (French tutor) and Alexis
6. Alexandra on deck
7. Nicholas and Alexandra with an officer
p. 29 1. Nicholas with Joy, Alexis' dog
2. Naval manoeuvers
3. Tatiana
4. Alexis
5. Naval manoeuvers
6. Pierre Gilliard and Alexis
7. The Empress on the Standart
p. 30 1. Nicholas
2. Nicholas with his daughters and officers
3. Nicholas
4. Nicholas, his daughters and an officer at the "farm" at Peterhof
5. Nicholas climbing a wooden tower during manoeuvers
6. At a military review - Nicholas mounted on horseback and Alexandra in an automobile, postcard
7. Nicholas with an officer on the Standart
p. 31: "Tennis" 1. Nicholas reading on the Empress' balcony at Tsarskoe Selo
2. Marie, an officer and the Emperor
3. Anna with tennis players
4. Anna's two nieces with their mother
5. The tennis group
6. "
7. "
8. Alexandra on the Standart
p. 32: "Krasnoe Selo - July 1914" 1. Grand Duke Nicholas Nicholaevitch with the Emperor, postcard
2. Nicholas reviewing troops at Krasnoe Selo, postcard
3. "God save the Tsar" - postcard with the declaration of World War I, 20 July 1914
4. Interior view of the Alexander Palace, portrait gallery
5. Nicholas reviewing troops at Krasnoe Selo, postcard
p. 33: Postcards 1. Nicholas and his officers on their way to a military review
2. The Emperor on the balcony of the Winter Palace following the formal declaration of war, 1914 July 20
3. The crowd in front of the Winter Palace, 1914 July 20
4. Arrival of the Imperial family at the Winter Palace for the ceremony of the declaration of war, 20 July 1914
p. 34: "Peterhof" 1. "Papa and Tanichka" (father and niece of Anna)
2. "Serezha and Tanichka" (Anna's brother and his daughter)
3. Serezha
4. "
5. Tanichka, Anna's niece
6. The Imperial family at lunch on the Standart
7. Olga in her Red Cross uniform and Maria
p. 35 1. Alexis with officers at Stavka, Russian military, headquarters during World War I
2. Olga and Tatiana in dining room, 2nd floor, Alexander Palace
3. Fountain in the garden of the Winter Palace
4. Anna's niece with her nurse
5. "
6. Tanichka and her sister
7. Alexandra
p. 36 1. Anna's nieces with their nurse
2. Grand Duke Nicholas and the Emperor at Stavka, postcard
3. Anna
4. Unidentified mother and child
5. The arrival of the Imperial family at the Winter Palace, postcard
6. Wounded officers
p. 37: "Her Majesty's Infirmary", Tsarskae Selo 1. Alexis at Stavka
2. Olga, Tatiana and the Empress with nurses, Drs. and patients, Hospital Tsarskae Selo
3. Olga knitting, mauve boudoir, Alexander Palace
4. Soldiers at Stavka
p. 38: The Empress's infirmary, Tsarskae Selo 1. The Empress, mauve boudoir, Alexander Palace
2. Alexandra and Tatiana dressing a wound
3. A wounded soldier
4. Alexandra and Tatiana in a dressing station
5. Lunch in the infirmary
6. Tatiana and Olga with wounded soldiers
7. A visit to Baranovichi (staff headquarters in 1914)
8. Alexis in the back entrance of the Alexander Palace
9. Anna with officers at Stavka
10. Olga at work in the infirmary
11. View of a ward
p. 39 1. Nicholas
2. Tatiana and Alexandra
3. Olga on a bicycle ride with Tatiana under arrest
4. Nicholas and his daughters under arrest
5. Nicholas, Tatiana and Alexandra
6. "Their Majesties' trip to Pskov"
7. Officers from the infirmary
8. Tatiana, mauve boudoir, Alexander Palace
9. Pskov
p. 40: The infirmary 1. The Empress, mauve boudoir
2. Olga with patients
3. Anna, Tatiana and Olga with patients - Alexandra can be seen in the top row
4. Olga in the Empress's mauve boudoir
5. Tatiana in a ward
6. Anna with patients
7. An operating room
8. A group of recuperating officers
p. 41: The infirmary 1. Anna with patients
2. Officers in recuperation
3. Anna with patients
4. A patient
5. Anna with doctors and a patient
6. Olga and Tatiana with patients and doctors
p. 42: The infirmary 1. Patients
2. Olga and Tatiana in a dressing station
3. The Empress and Tatiana and Olga in a ward
4. Officer exhibiting wound
5. The Empress with Tatiana and Olga in a ward
6. Close-up of a wound
p. 43 1. Anna and the Empress with two patients
2. "
3. The Empress
4. Marie and Anastasia
5. The Empress
6. The Empress with patients
7. The Empress
p. 44 1. Anna, the Empress, Tatiana and Olga in an operating room
2. Olga, Anna, the Empress and Tatiana with patients in a ward
3. The Empress working on a head wound - in the operating room Tatiana, Anna and Olga look on.
4. In a ward - Olga, Tatiana and Anna
5. In a ward - Olga and the Empress, Anna and Tatiana in the background
p. 45 1. Nicholas with an officer at Stavka
2. Anna, Tatiana, the Empress, and Olga posing in Red Cross uniforms
3. Nicholas and Alexandra with patients of the infirmary
4. Nicholas with Generals Yanushkevitch and Ruzsky
5. Staff officers
6. Olga and Tatiana with recuperating patients
p. 46 1. In the operating room - Olga dressing a wound, Anna holding the officer's arm
2. In the operating room - Tatiana cleaning a wound, Alexandra looking on
3. Olga and Tatiana in a ward
4. Nicholas and Alexis on a hike at Stavka
5. Olga and Tatiana in a ward
6. Alexis and his friends being pulled on a wagon by Nagorny at Alexandria Dacha, Peterhof
7. Tatiana with patients
8. A woman doctor with patients in a ward
p. 47 1. The patients are feeling better
2. Olga and Tatiana with patients
3. The Empress and her daughters with patients
4. Recuperating officers doing a sword dance on the ward chairs - nurses look on horrified
5. A sword fight in the ward
6. Dancing on the bed
7. The Catherine Palace at Tsarskoe Selo, where infirmary was located
8. Nurses and patients in a ward
9. "
10. "
11. "
12. Patients of the infirmary
p. 48 1. Patients of the infirmary
2. The Empress with her camera, the infirmary in the background
3. Marie and Anastasia in a ward
4. ?
5. Marie and Anastasia visiting patients
6. The infirmary
7. Alexandra and her daughters getting into their automobile
8. Olga in her Red Cross uniform
9. A nurse with soldiers
10. Lower Dacha-Aleksandria-Peterhof
p. 49 1. Nurses at table
2. Tatiana, the Empress and Olga standing outside
3. Tatiana with Anna and officers
4. Outside the infirmary with auto, soldiers, and nurses
5. Tatiana, the Empress, and Olga standing inside the infirmary
6. Balcony
7. Officers in recuperation
8. A doctor with sentry at the entrance to the infirmary
9. Nurses and a patient at lunch
10. Officers sword fighting at the entrance
11. House of Anna Vyrubova
12. In a ward - soldiers and a nurse
p. 50 1. A patient at his sink
2. Officers relaxing outside
3. Officers relaxing
4. Nurse and patients
5. Anna and patients
6. Anna, Tatiana, Olga, and Alexandra in a ward
7. Olga, the Empress, Tatiana, and Anna with the infirmary staff
8. Olga and patients
9. The Empress on balcony of Alexander Palace
10. Patients and a nurse
p. 51: Scenes in the infirmary 1. Doctors, nurses, and patients
2. "
3. "
4. "
5. "
6. "
7. Serezha, Anna's brother, and his wife, Ena
p. 52 1. Anna in bed following her injury in a train accident, February 1915
2. Serezha and Ena
3. Anna's mother and unidentified mother in the drawing room of Anna's house
4. The Empress visiting Anna
5. Princess T. visiting Anna
6. Anna's mother
p. 53 1. Anna in bed at her house at Tsarskoe Selo
2. The Empress on her balcony
3. Anna in recuperation from her accident on the Empress's balcony
4. Anna in bed at her cottage
5. Alexis
6. Anna in bed, in recuperation
7. Alexis
p. 54 1. Nicholas on the Empress's balcony
2. Nicholas and Alexis reviewing sailors
3. The Empress with her daughters
4. Alexis with his parents on the Empress's balcony
5. Alexandra in mourning dress, balcony, Alexander Palace
6. Marie, Tatiana, and Olga (seated) in mourning
p. 55a: A Visit to Serezha and His Family (Anna's brother) 1. Tanichka and her sister Olga
2. Serezha, his wife and his sister Alya
3. Olga
4. "Serezha and Mama"
5. Tanichka and Olga
6. "
7. Serezha and his wife
8. Olga and her nurse
p. 55b 1. Alya and her children (Anna's sister-in-law)
2. "
3. The children of Anna's sister
4. The Empress's drawing room, the Alexander Palace
5. Alya's children
6. The baby with her nurse
7. One of Anna's nieces
8. The Empress's drawing room, the Alexander Palace
9. Anna's niece
10. Front, private (Imperial) entrance to the Alexander Palace
p. 56 1. Anna's family
2. Anna's family at A.V.'s house, Tsarskoe Selo
3. Anna in her wheelchair following the train accident
4. On the Imperial train - Grand Duke Dmitri, Nicholas, Alexandra, Michael (Nicholas' brother), Anastasia, Marie, seated, Tatiana and Olga.
5. Anna's family
6. "
7. Alexandra's corner drawing room, the Alexander Palace
8. Anna's family
9. "
10. "
11. "
p. 57 1. Alexandra arranging flowers
2. The Empress with her flower arrangement
3. "
4. The Empress
5. Tatiana with a Cossack officer
6. Olga
7. A portrait of Alexandra
8. Anna's relatives
p. 58 1. Alexandra working on her embroidery
2. Olga and Anastasia with their mother on Empress' balcony, Alexander Palace
3. Alexandra working on her embroidery on Empress' balcony, Alexander Palace
4. Alexandra picking wild flowers
5. Tatiana and her mother gathering wild flowers
6. Anna Vyrubova on Empress' balcony, Alexander Palace
p. 59 1. Anna's father with his daughter-in-law and granddaughters
2. The little girls (Anna's nieces) with their mother
3. General Taneev (Anna's father) with granddaughters and daughter-in-law
4. Nini Voeikov (wife of General Voeikov)
5. Alexandra reading on her chaise in the mauve boudoir
Back cover: Photographs of the family in exile. 1. Alexandra doing needlework in her wheelchair in the park of the Alexander Palace, spring 1917 (under arrest)
2. The ballroom converted to a chapel at the Governor's house in Tobolsk
3. The Imperial spading the ground for a vegetable garden behind the Alexander Palace, 1917 April - Tatiana carrying a litter of dirt, Nicholas standing with spade in hand
4. Alexis and a nurse, circa 1916
The contents of Albums 4-7 have not been fully listed, however, in many cases individual images have captions.
Russia -- History -- Nicholas II, 1894-1917; Russia -- Kings and rulers; Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Alekseĭ Nikolaevich, Czarevitch, son of Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, 1904-1918; Alexandra, Empress, consort of Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, 1872-1918; Anastasii︠a︡ Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess, daughter of Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, 1901-1918; Marīi︠a︡ Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess, daughter of Nicholas I, Emperor of Russia, 1819-1876; Nicholas, Emperor of Russia, II, 1868-1918 -- Family; Nicholas, Emperor of Russia, II, 1868-1918; Olʹga Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess, daughter of Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, 1895-1918; Den, Lili, 1888-1963; Rasputin, Grigoriĭ Efimovich, 1869-1916; Tati︠a︡na Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess, daughter of Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, 1897-1918; Vyrubova, Anna Aleksandrovna, 1884-1964; Romanov, House of -- Portraits; Romanov, House of; T︠S︡arskoselʹskiĭ dvoret︠s︡
- Correspondence, 1913-1928; Series I; 0.4; (1 box)
  - LETTERS TO ANNA VYRUBOVA
    - From the Imperial Family
      - Alexandra, Empress
        - APCS, photostat, 1917 Jun 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - ALS, with envelope, [1917 Aug] (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - APCS, 1917 Oct 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - ALS, 1917 Oct 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - TL, 1917 Nov 24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - ALS, 1917 Dec 8 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - APCS, 1917 Dec 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - ALS, 1917 Dec 15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - ALS, marked "T[obol'sk] 1", 1918 Jan 9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - ALS, marked "II", 1918 Jan 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - APCS, marked "No. 3", 1918 Jan 17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - ALS, marked "No. 5 T[obol'sk]", 1918 Jan 22 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - ALS, marked "No. 6", 1918 Jan 23-24 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - ALS, marked "No. 7", 1918 Feb 5 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - ALS, marked "No. 9", 1918 Mar 2/15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          Scope and Contents
          Letter dated 1918 Mar 2/14
        - ALS, marked "No. 10", 1918 Mar 3/16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - ALS, marked "12", 1918 Mar 26 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - ALS, marked "13", 1918 Apr 2 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - ALS, marked "14", 1918 Apr 19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - APCS, marked "15", 1918 [Apr] 3/21 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - ALS, marked "16", 1918 Apr 10/23 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - ALS fragment, signed "Annushka", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - AL fragments, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Aleksei Nikolaevich, Grand Duke
        - APC, with drawing by Empress Alexandra, 1917 Nov 24 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - ALS, 1918 Dec 10 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - ALS, 1918 Jan 22 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - [Anastasiia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess?]
        - ALS, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Mariia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess
        - APCS, 1918 Jan (Box 1, Folder 28)
        - ALS, 1918 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 29)
          Includes notes from Emperor Nicholas II and Empress Alexandra With two photographs of Emperor Nicholas II with children
        - ALS, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Nicholas II, Emperor
        - ALS, 1917 Dec 10 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Ol'ga Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess
        - ALS, 1917 Dec 10 (Box 1, Folder 32)
        - APCS, 1918 Jan 22 (Box 1, Folder 33)
        - ALS, 1918 Feb 5/18 (Box 1, Folder 34)
          Letter dated 1918 Feb 5/17 Includes notes by Grand Duchesses Tat'iana and Mariia Nikolaevna
        - APCS, 1918 [Apr] (Box 1, Folder 35)
        - APC, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Tat'iana Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess
        - ALS, 1917 Dec 9 (Box 1, Folder 37)
        - ALS, 1917 Dec 10 (Box 1, Folder 38)
        - APCS, 1918 Jan 22 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - From Others
      - Gilliard, Pierre, 1918 Jan 18 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Romanova, Anna Pavlovna, 1918 Jan 25 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Volkov, Aleksei. 3 ALS, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - LETTERS TO LILI DEHN (SMOL'SKAIA) FROM THE IMPERIAL FAMILY
    - Alexandra, Empress
      - APCS, 1916 Mar 10 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - APC (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Apr 10 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Apr 19 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - AL, with envelope, 1917 Apr 30 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - APC (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - ALS (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - ALS (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jun 5 (Box 1, Folder 55)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jun 8 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - AL (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jun 13 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jul 2 (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jul 11 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      - ALS (Box 1, Folder 61)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jul 19 (Box 1, Folder 62)
      - ALS (Box 1, Folder 63)
        Includes notes from Grand Duke Aleksei Nikolaevich and Grand Duchess Ol'ga Nikolaevna With note from Lili Dehn
      - AL, drawing by Empress Alexandra, 1917 Nov 29 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      - AL, with envelope, 1917 Dec 5 (Box 1, Folder 65)
      - APC, drawn by Empress Alexandra, with prayers in French and Slavonic, 1917 Dec 5 (Box 1, Folder 66)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Dec 27 (Box 1, Folder 67)
      - AL fragment, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Anastasiia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess
      - APCS, 1917 Apr 10 (Box 1, Folder 69)
      - APCS, 1917 Jun 5 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Mariia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess
      - APCS, 1917 [Apr 8] (Box 1, Folder 71)
      - APCS, 1917 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 72)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 73)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jun 11 (Box 1, Folder 74)
      - APCS fragment, 1917 Jun 30 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Ol'ga Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Apr 3 (Box 1, Folder 76)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Apr 10 (Box 1, Folder 77)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Apr 15 (Box 1, Folder 78)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Apr 19 (Box 1, Folder 79)
        Includes note by Grand Duchess Tat'iana Nikolaevna
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Apr 27 (Box 1, Folder 80)
        Includes note by Empress Alexandra
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Apr 30 (Box 1, Folder 81)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 82)
      - APCS, 1917 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 83)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 84)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 85)
      - ALS (Box 1, Folder 86)
      - APCS, 1917 Jun 5 (Box 1, Folder 87)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jun 10 (Box 1, Folder 88)
      - APCS, 1917 Jun 30 (Box 1, Folder 89)
      - ALS (Box 1, Folder 90)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1918 Jan 6 (Box 1, Folder 91)
        Letter dated 1917 Jan 6
    - Tat'iana Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jan 12 (Box 1, Folder 92)
      - ALS (Box 1, Folder 93)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 94)
      - ALS (Box 1, Folder 95)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Jul 24 (Box 1, Folder 96)
      - ALS, with envelope, 1917 Nov 19 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - MICELLANEOUS LETTERS
    - Gendrikova, Anastasiia, Countess, to Empress Alexandra, ALS with notations by Alexandra (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Nicholas II, Emperor, to A. N. Naryshkina, ALS with envelope, 1913 Jan 2 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Rasputin, Grigorii, to Emperor Nicholas II, ALS (Box 1, Folder 100)
- Photographs, 1894-1935; Series II; 6.5; (7 boxes)
  - ALBUMS
    The original photo albums are filed as Restricted Fragile Papers, and may only be consulted with permission of the appropriate curator. Photographic facsimiles have been provided for general reference use.
    - Album 2, 1912-13 (Box 2, Folder 101)
      Related Archival Materials note